（中央公园咖啡厅）
Out of all of us, who do you think will get married next?
我们所有人里 你想下一个结婚的会是谁？
Probably Monica and Chandler.
大概是摩妮卡和钱德
Could I have a pack of Newport Lights?
给我一包新港淡烟？
We don't sell cigarettes, but they do across the street.
我们没有卖烟，对街有卖
That'd be great. Thanks.
那太好了，谢谢
Melissa Worbert. I don't think I have the energy for this.
马利莎伍伯，我没有力气应付她
Oh, my God! Ray-Ray Greene?
我的天！瑞瑞葛林？
怎么样？！
You've been MlA for seven sorority newsletters.
你是我们社团连续7期周报主角
What's up with you?
你怎么样？
Why don't I tell you over here?
我们到那边去再说？
So last I heard you were gonna get married.
上次我听说你要结婚了
Poor Ray-Ray.
可怜的瑞瑞
Oh, no. It's all good.
不，其实很好
-I actually work at Ralph Lauren. -Shut up!
-我现在替洛夫罗兰工作 -闭嘴！
I will not. I'm the divisional head of men's sportswear.
我不，我是男装运动服饰的分区主管
Shut up more! Are you friends with Ralph?
再闭嘴！你是洛夫的朋友吗？
-Oh, please. -Are you?
-拜托 -你是吗？
No.
不是
We have to have dinner. What are you doing tomorrow?
我们一定要一起吃饭 你明天做什么？
-Tomorrow. I don't know. -You're having dinner with me.
-明天，我不知道 -你要和我吃晚饭
Shut up.
闭嘴
I've gotta go. This has been so great.
我要走了，看到你真好
Oh, there you are.
哦，这儿
So listen, just call me. Here's my card.
打电话给我，这是我的名片
-You're in real estate? -No, that's an old card.
-你在做房地产？ -不，那是旧名片
I got out of that to do something where I could...
我必须离开那工作去做些…
help people and make a difference.
可以帮助别人和改变什么的工作
What do you do now?
现在你做什么？
I'm a party planner.
宴会规划
-I'll see you tomorrow. -Okay.
-明天见 -好
Look who's back. It's Ray-Ray.
看谁回来了，是瑞瑞
That was my friend, Melissa, from college.
那是我大学的朋友马利莎
She seems really, really fun!
她看起来很有意思！
She's actually sweet, and we used to be very close.
她真的很甜，我们曾经很亲近
Wait a minute. She's not the one who you...?
等一下，她不是那个你…？
Who you what? Who you what?
你怎样？你怎样？
-Yes. -Wow!
-是 -哇！
Wow, what? Who you what?
哇，什么？你怎样？
Oh, it's not a big deal.
没什么大不了
They were lovers.
他们是情人
-What? -What?
-什么？ -什么？
No, we weren't. It was nothing.
不，我们不是情人，没有什么
It was one night, senior year, and we went to a party...
大四的一天晚上，我们去参加舞会…
had a lot of sangria, and you know, ended up...
喝了很多桑格利塔，你知道，结果…
kissing for a bit.
我们接吻了
So that's two of my wives.
我的两个老婆都是同性恋
The One With Rachel's Big Kiss
本集播出：瑞秋的吻
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
So this is where the band is. And here's the bar.
这是乐队的所在，这儿是吧台
And all these pins have people's names on them. Rach, here you are.
这些大头针上有人名 瑞秋，你在这里
Why don't we just put me with a Manhattan in my hand...
为什么不给我一杯曼哈顿…
talking to the cute bartender.
让我和可爱的酒保聊天
These pins aren't for playing, are they?
这些大头针不是用来玩的，是不？
The red are my guests, and the blue are yours.
红的是我的客人，蓝色的是你的
This is so sad. I only have like 10 pins.
真可怜，我只有10个客人
Chandler, relax. It's not a contest.
钱德，轻松一点，这不是比赛
Certainly not a close one.
不是实力相近的比赛
Hey, Rach.
瑞秋
Stop picturing it!
不要再想了！
I think that's it. The seating chart is done. This is our wedding.
我想这样可以了，座位表好了 这是我们的婚礼
They all look like they're having fun.
他们看来玩得很开心，不是吗
So where are my parents gonna be?
我爸妈坐哪里？
Well, if this is the wedding hall...
如果这是结婚礼堂…
your parents would be over here at home in Queens.
你父母会在皇后区的家里
They're not invited? Oh, no, they're gonna be crushed!
他们没有被邀请？ 不，他们一定会很伤心！
Why would they think they're invited?
为什么他们以为会被邀请呢？
You got me. I don't...
你问倒我了，我不…
-Joey! -Look, I thought parents were coming.
-乔伊！ -我以为父母都会来
Your parents are coming. Chandler's are coming.
你的父母会来，钱德的父母也会来
Ross' parents are coming.
罗斯的父母也会来
Ross' parents are my parents.
罗斯的父母就是我的父母
Well, see, parents are coming.
看，父母们都会来
-We should invite them. -You just want more blue pins.
-我们应该请他们 -你只是想要更多的蓝色大头针
Well, this is just sad.
这实在太惨了
All right. Maybe I can fit them in if I just do some rearranging.
好，也许能把他们排进来 不过要重新安排位子
Rachel may have to sit at the bar.
瑞秋可能要坐在吧台
That is not a problem.
没有问题
-Maybe you'll order a little sangria. -Get out of here!
-也许你可以叫一杯桑格丽塔 -去你的！
These are our tuxedos. If you like anything, we can make a deal.
这是我们的礼服 如果有你喜欢的，可以便宜些
Anything at all. But these are the three that Monica pre-approved.
全部都可以 但这三件是摩妮卡先核准的
Thanks a lot for hooking me up.
谢谢你替我们拉到关系
And I want you to know that I want you to attend our wedding as my guest.
我想请你参加我们的婚礼做我的客人
I'm Monica's maid of honor.
我是摩妮卡的伴娘
Okay, don't try to blue-pin me.
别想把我变成蓝色大头针
-Well, these look nice. -They are nice.
-这些不错 -是不错
When celebrities are done with them, they send them back.
名人穿过这些之后，就送回来这儿
-You mean like for award shows? -Some of them.
-你是指像颁奖典礼之后？ -有些是
They've been down the red carpet with people yelling...
它们都上过红地毯，被人叫着：
"Who are you wearing? You look fabulous!"
“你穿的是谁的？你看来棒极了！”
Might I suggest watching a little more ESPN...
容我建议您多看一点ESPN…
and a little less E!.
少看一点艺人八卦节目！
Okay. Who wore those?
谁穿过这些？
-Well, this one's Tom Brokaw. -Not bad.
-这是汤姆布鲁克穿过的 -不错嘛
This one is Paul O'Neill.
这是保罗欧尼尔穿过的
Who's that?
他是谁？
He plays for the Yankees. Seriously, ESPN.
他是洋基队的球员 真的，多看ESPN
Just once in a while. Have it on in the background.
有的时候，开着它当背景也好
-This one was Pierce Brosnan. -Pierce Brosnan?
-这是皮尔斯布鲁斯南穿过的 -皮尔斯布鲁斯南？
Are you serious?
真的吗？
007?
007？
This is James Bond's tux? I have to get married in James Bond's tux.
这是詹姆士庞德的燕尾服？我一定要 穿詹姆士庞德的燕尾服结婚
It's a pretty cool tux.
很酷
It's not just that. I would be England's most powerful weapon.
不只如此，我会是 英格兰最强力的武器
A jet-setting heartbreaker on Her Majesty's secret service.
女王陛下的秘密特务 四处旅游的断肠人
A man who fears no one, with a license to kill.
有着杀人执照，什么都不怕的男人
Would Monica let me wear this?
摩妮卡会不会让我穿这件？
We should really learn how to play the real way.
我们应该学真正的玩法
I like our way.
我喜欢我们的玩法
Chess!
将军！
-Nice move. -Yeah.
-走的好 -是啊
I hooked Ross and Chandler up with tuxedos. Do you need one?
我替罗斯和钱德找到 燕尾服，你需要吗？
No, I'm not wearing a tux.
不，我不穿燕尾服
-What are you gonna wear? -Multi-colored robes.
-你要穿什么？ -多彩的袍子
And maybe a hat.
也许戴一顶帽子
-Does Monica know about this? -No.
-摩妮卡知道吗？ -不
Can I please be there when you tell her?
你告诉她时我可以在场吗？
You want to go to a movie tonight?
晚上要不要去看电影？
I'm having dinner with Melissa.
我要和马利莎吃饭
Can I come?
我可以来吗？
I won't talk. You'll just hear my video camera.
我不说话，你只会听见 我的摄影机的声音
-What? What's going on? -Can I tell her?
-什么？怎么回事？ -我可以告诉她吗？
Do you want what happened, or Joey's lewd version?
你要真正发生的事 还是乔伊的淫荡版本？
Joey's.
-乔伊的 -好
I had this college friend...
我有一个大学朋友…
and I made the mistake of telling Joey that one time...
我不应该告诉乔伊有一次…
she and I, you know, kissed a little bit.
她和我接吻了
Yeah, I'm sure that happened.
是啊，我相信有的
-It did. -Sure.
-真的 -当然
Hey. It happened.
真的发生了
It was senior year. It was after the Sigma Chi luau...
是大四那年，那是一次社团聚会…
and Melissa and I got very drunk.
我和马利莎喝得大醉
And we ended up kissing. For several minutes.
结果我们两个接吻了 好几分钟呢
Which means she had a couple spritzers and a peck on the cheek.
意思是她喝了几杯，轻轻吻在脸颊上
Why are you taking this away from me?
你为什么要夺走这件事呢？
Why is it so hard for you to believe?
为什么这么难让你相信？
Okay. I just didn't know that you were a lesbian.
好吧，我不知道你是同性恋
I'm not saying that I'm a lesbian. I'm just saying that this happened.
我不是说我是同性恋 我只是说那件事发生了
It just seems pretty wild. And you're so...
只是觉得很狂野，你是这么地…
vanilla.
乖宝宝
Vanilla? I'm not vanilla. I do lots of crazy things.
乖宝宝？我不是乖宝宝 我做很多疯狂的事
I mean, I got drunk and married in Vegas.
我喝醉了，在拉斯维加斯结婚
To Ross.
和罗斯
If you don't believe me...
如果你不相信我…
just come with me to dinner tonight and she'll tell you.
今晚和我一起去吃饭，她会告诉你
Okay. Because I can't picture it.
好吧，可是我想像不出来
You should get inside my head.
你该看看我脑袋里的划面
Guess what I got for your wedding?
猜我为你的婚礼弄到什么？
A freakishly thin date with a hanger for a head?
头像挂衣架，瘦巴巴的伴？
Rachel hooked me up with a tux. But not just any tux.
瑞秋替我弄到一件燕尾服 但不是随便一件
Batman's tux!
是蝙蝠侠的！
-What? -That's right.
-什么？ -没错
Made expressly for Val Kilmer, and worn by him in the hit film...
特别定做给方基墨的 让他穿在票房冠军电影…
that Batman film he was in.
那部他演的蝙蝠侠电影里
You can't wear that. I'm wearing the famous tux.
你不能穿那件 我要穿名人的燕尾服
If you wear that, it'll make mine less special.
怎样？如果你穿那件 会让我的不那么特别的
You need something to to make it special?
你需要用一些东西来让那天特别吗？
You have the most special thing of all.
喂！你有了最特别的一样
You are marrying the woman you love.
你娶了你爱的女人
Don't take away my cool thing. Pretty please?
不要抢走我的锋头，拜托？
"Pretty please?" Not very 007.
“拜托？”不怎么007
If you were getting married, I'd never do anything to upset you.
如果你要结婚 我不会做任何让你生气的事
-You slept with my sister. -That was pretty 007.
-你和我妹妹上床 -那很007
All right, I figured it out.
好，你来了 好，我想出办法来了
I'm gonna take 2 tables of 8, add your parents...
我把8个人的这两桌，加上你父母…
and make them into 3 tables of 6.
变成6个人的三桌
And I called the caterer. We are good to go!
我已经通知了办席的人，都弄好了！
Yeah. They're not coming.
他们不来了
What?
什么？
They think that you only invited them because of me.
他们觉得你是因为我才邀请他们的
They feel unwanted.
他们觉得不被欢迎
That's too bad. It's true. But too bad.
真糟糕，是真的，但真糟糕
If you could just call my mom.
你可以打电话给我妈
Just let her know you want them there.
让她知道你希望他们去
This is a woman who has sent you many lasagnas.
她送过你很多很多千层面
No, she hasn't.
不，她没有
Is it her fault if some didn't make it to you?
有些没送到你手里不是她的错
What am I gonna say?
我要说什么？
Tell them you mixed up invitations. No, blame it on the post office.
告诉她请帖搞乱了，不，怪邮局好了
They hate the post office. And the Irish.
他们最恨邮局，还有爱尔兰人
But I don't think you could blame it on them.
不过我想你不能怪到他们头上
Hello? Yeah, hi. Mrs. Tribbianni? This is Monica Geller.
喂？你好，崔比亚尼太太？ 我是摩妮卡盖勒
I'm just calling to say that I really hope you can make the wedding.
我想告诉你我们很希望 你们能来参加婚礼
Apparently some of our invitations weren't delivered.
我们很多请帖都没寄到
I guess there was some screw-up at the damn post office.
我猜又是可恶的邮局搞砸的
Tell me about it!
就是嘛！
Yeah, the U.S. Post Office? No. More like U.S. Lost Office.
什么美国邮局嘛？更像是美国遗失局
What are they, Irish?
他们搞什么嘛，都是爱尔兰人吗？
Anyway, his name's Allen. And we've been going out for three years.
他叫艾伦，我们在一起三年了
He was my first client when I became a party planner.
他是我做宴会规划的第一位客户
He was actually planning a party for his girlfriend at the time.
那时他正要规划给他女朋友的宴会
Oh, well.
嗯
-He was Theta Beta Pi at Syracuse. -That's great.
-他是雪城大学贝塔拍社团的 -真好
-Were you ever in a sorority? -Of course.
-你参加过社团吗？ -当然
Yes. I was a Thigh Mega Tampon.
我是大腿大卫生棉条的成员
What one?
哪一个？
We were huge too. But they had to shut us down...
我们也很庞大，但后来被关掉了…
when Regina Phalangie died of alcohol poisoning.
因为芮吉娜菲兰基死于酒精中毒
Isn't it a shame when one girl ruins it for the whole bunch?
真是糟糕，一个女孩就毁了大家
Anyway...
不管了…
Speaking of drinking too much, I told Phoebe...
讲到喝太多，我告诉菲比…
about that crazy night after the Sigma Chi luau where we made out.
在席格犸社很疯那晚，我们亲吻的事
What?
什么？
Remember we.. Come on, we had sarongs on and the coconut bikini tops.
记得我们…我们穿着沙龙 还有椰子壳比基尼上衣
We went back to the house and got really silly...
之后我们回到家，在那儿疯癫…
and we made out.
然后我们接吻了
Wow, Ray-Ray, I have no idea what you're talking about.
瑞瑞，我不知道你在说什么
Really?
真的？
Ross is Batman.
罗斯是蝙蝠侠
Well, he did manage to keep his identity secret for a long time.
他是把身份掩护了很久
Rachel got Ross the tuxedo that Val Kilmer wore in Batman.
瑞秋替罗斯弄到 方基墨在蝙蝠侠里穿的燕尾服
Batman is so much cooler than James Bond.
蝙蝠侠比詹姆士庞德酷多了
-What? 007 has all those gadgets. -Batman has a utility belt.
-什么？007有很多的工具 -蝙蝠侠有工具腰带
-007 has a fancy car. -Batman has the Batmobile.
-007有很炫的车 -蝙蝠侠有蝙蝠车
-007 gets all the ladies. -Batman has Robin.
-007有很多女人 -蝙蝠侠有罗宾
We get ESPN, right?
我们有ESPN台，对吧？
How about you go put on your 007 tuxedo, and I'll make you a martini?
你何不穿上你的007燕尾服 我替你调一杯马丁尼
I don't like martinis.
我不喜欢马丁尼
-A Yoo-Hoo with a funny straw? -Yum.
-一杯摇摇饮料，用一只搞笑吸管？ -好的
I know the invitation says 6 p.m.
请帖上写晚上6点
But does that mean get there at 6, or the show starts at 6?
是指6点入席，还是6点开始表演？
The show?
“表演”？
Right, the wedding. Gotcha.
对，婚礼，知道了
But weddings start a little late, right?
不过婚礼会晚一点开始，对不？
Have you ever been to one of my weddings?
你有参加过我规划的婚礼吗？
Well, it's the same day as my niece's christening...
那天我侄女受洗…
and I want my parents to see me.
我希望我父母能看到我
My part's in the beginning. I'm not in the rest of the show.. Wedding.
我的部份是在开始时 不在其他部份的表演…婚礼
The wedding starts at 6.
婚礼6点开始
Okay. I totally hear you.
好，我听到了
How about this? I vamp till they get there.
这样如何？我可以表演到他们到达
You'll "vamp"?
你要“表演”？
Like warm up the crowd. Ask where they're from.
像是和观众打打屁，问他们从哪儿来
In Joey Tribbiani, you get a minister and an entertainer.
因为乔伊崔比亚尼在时 你有教士和演艺人员
I'm a "ministainer."
我是一位“教演人”
There's no one better. There's no one greater.
没有更好的，没有更伟大的
How can you not remember us kissing?
你怎能不记得我们接吻的事？
I don't know. I don't remember a lot of things that never happened.
我不知道，我不记得那些 从没发生过的事
Remember, we were on the sleeping porch? We couldn't stop giggling.
记得我们在睡觉的廊子里 一直笑一直笑？
Our coconuts kept knocking together.
我们的椰子壳撞在一起
Somewhere Joey's head is exploding.
乔伊的头在某处爆炸了
I don't want to make you uncomfortable...
我不想让你不舒服…
but I told Phoebe it happened, and she doesn't believe me.
但我告诉菲比发生的事，她不相信我
I'm sorry. I mean, if I thought it happened, I would say it.
对不起，如果我认为 它发生了，我会承认的
Maybe I passed out and you did stuff to me while I was sleeping.
也许我昏过去了 你在我睡觉时对我做了什么
It's okay, you don't have to do this. I believe you.
没关系，你不必这么做，我相信你
If you say you kissed Melissa, then you kissed Melissa.
如果你说你吻了马利莎 那么你就吻了马利莎
-Thank you, Phoebe. -Okay.
-谢谢，菲比 -好
-But she didn't. -I know.
-可是她没有 -我知道
You carry that around?
你带着它走来走去？
I find it to be something of a conversation piece.
是的，我发现它是个好话题
-Between you and...? -Gunther.
-和…？ -阿甘
Why don't we put them on?
我们何不穿上？
Get a picture of Batman and James Bond, together.
拍一张蝙蝠侠和 詹姆士庞德一起的照片
I would, but my pants are a little tight.
我很愿意，但我的裤子小了一点
A little tight? I could see 00 and 7 in those things.
小了一点？我可以看到 里面的两个0和一个7
I was looking forward to wearing our celebrity tuxes together.
真糟糕 我很期待我们一起穿名人燕尾服呢
-So you're not gonna be wearing yours? - Are you kidding? It's Batman's tux!
-你不穿你的了？ -你开玩笑？是蝙蝠侠的燕尾服！
Let me try it on.
我试穿看看
Okay. But just the jacket. 00 and 7 are not getting in there.
好，只有外套 两个0和一个7不要进去
Holy double-vented comfort, Batman!
双面通风的舒适，蝙蝠侠！
What's this?
这是什么？
An invitation to the At First Sight premiere?
《真情难舍》首映请帖？
Val Kilmer didn't wear this in Batman.
方基墨没有在《蝙蝠侠》里穿这件
He wore it to the premiere of a fruity love story where he was a blind guy.
他穿这件去参加 他演瞎子的那部文艺爱情片首映
Let me see that.
给我看
Oh, man.
老天
The only super power you have is the slightly heightened sense of smell.
你唯一的超能力是稍微强化的嗅觉
Can I talk to you guys for a second?
可以和你们谈谈吗？
I give up. Whatever you want, you can have it.
我放弃了，你要怎样就怎样吧
You want to sing a song or do a dance?
你要唱歌还是跳舞？
You want your mom at the altar screaming racial slurs? I don't care.
还是要你妈在祭坛前 尖叫种族崎视的字眼？我都不在乎
I just want to thank you guys for what you did for my parents.
我只是要谢谢你们为我父母做的一切
They're so happy to be a part of your special day.
他们很高兴能参加你们特别的一天
Tell them we're glad they're coming.
告诉他们我们很高兴他们会来
I will. Oh, check out what they got me to wear for the ceremony!
我会的，看看他们替我准备 参加婚礼的衣服！
I wear it like this when I marry you guys. And then this...
我替你们证婚时这样穿，然后…
is for party time.
在宴会时这样穿
It happened. I am telling you it happened.
它发生了，我告诉你它发生了
It was great meeting you.
很高兴认识你
And, Rachel? I don't think I'll be calling you because...
瑞秋？我想我不会 打电话给你，因为…
you know, you've gotten weird.
你变得好奇怪
Take care, you guys.
保重，两位
Wait a minute. Okay, look.
等一下，好，听着
That night was the one wild thing I've ever done in my life.
那天晚上是我所做过 最狂野的一件事
I won't let you take it away.
我不会让你夺去它
So if you don't remember that, maybe you'll remember this...
如果你不记得那件事 也许你会记得这个…
Oh, my God. You love me.
我的天，你爱我
What?
什么？
Of course I remember. I think about it all the time.
我当然记得，这些日子里我一直想着它
I can still hear the coconuts knocking together...
我还能听到椰子壳碰在一起的声音…
I didn't want to tell you, because I didn't think you'd return my love...
我不想告诉你，因为我不觉得 你会回报我的爱…
Look who's being suddenly shy.
看是谁突然变得害羞
You have to feel what I feel.
你一定和我一样感觉
Nobody can kiss that good and not mean it.
没人能不是真心而吻得那么好
I'm just a good kisser.
我的吻功很好
Shut up.
闭嘴
I'm sorry.
对不起
You don't have to be sorry.
你不必抱歉
I'm obviously kidding.
我在开玩笑
I'm not in love with you. I'm not in love with her.
我没爱上你，我没爱上她
I don't hear coconuts banging together.
我没听到椰子壳撞在一起
I don't picture your face when I make love to my boyfriend.
我和男友做爱时没幻想你的脸
Anyway, I gotta go.
我要走了
A kiss goodbye?
亲一下再见？
No? Okay.
不要？好吧
I mean, I had no idea that that would...
我不知道那会…
What the hell was that?
这是怎么回事？
Just wanted to see what all the fuss was about.
想看看这一场混乱是怎么来的
-And? -I've had better.
-然后？ -我有过更好的
I found one that fits.
我找到一件合身的
Well, you know what they say? 23rd time's a charm.
是啊，人们常说 第23次是最好的一次
Look at you, all handsome.
看看你，好英俊
-Whose is it? -Does it matter?
-是谁穿过的？ -有关系吗？
All that matters is that you look so handsome.
唯一重要的是你看来很英俊
-Whose is it? -I don't want to say.
-是谁的？ -我不想讲
Come on, I don't care. Whose is it?
我不在乎，是谁的？
Diane Keaton.
黛安基顿